SURAJ MOHAMMED

Phone:9591701998

Email:mdsuraj.13@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/suraj-mohammed/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A motivated individual with an innate ability to communicate, I am a sales and marketing professional with over 3 years of experience. Recognized as a team player with leadership skills. I am looking for an opportunity that allows me to grow, both personally and professionally.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Sep. 2019 – Oct. 2020 Bangalore, Karnataka

Corporate Sales Manager, Vastech Solutions Pvt Ltd

- Building a full scale B2B sales operation from the ground-up
- Conduct market surveys in order to obtain information about potential customers
- Handling PAN India and APAC enterprise clients, strategic collaborations & partnerships
- Contract negotiations and client relationship management
- Setting sales and marketing SOP to streamline company's lead generation communication

Jun. 2018 – Sep. 2019 Bangalore, Karnataka

\

Marketing Analyst, Sowparnika Retail Pvt Ltd (Inter Company Transfer)

- Identify, develop, and evaluate marketing strategy, based on knowledge of establishment objectives, market characteristics, and cost and mark-up factors
- Developing loyalty programs, promotions and managing reward points
- Coordinate and participate in promotional activities or trade shows, working with advertisers and event managers
- Driving growth by executing effective customer acquisition and retention programs
- Customer focus and stake holder management by executing effective customer acquisition and retention programs

Jun. 2017 – Jun. 2018 Bangalore, Karnataka

Business Development Engineer, Purnatva Solutions Pvt Ltd (Now Micelio Mobility Pvt Ltd)

- Building B2B sales by prospecting and qualifying leads
- Nurturing qualified leads, on-boarding customers and contract negotiations
- Researching and analyzing the market to find out better business opportunities
- Maintaining client relationship by escalations and account conflicts
- Responsible for creating and monitoring company's digital marketing campaign

Apr. 2016 – May. 2016 Bangalore, Karnataka Sales and Marketing intern, Purnatva Solutions Pvt Ltd

Jun. 2017 – Jun. 2018 Bangalore, Karnataka Summer Intern, ITC Ltd

EDUCATION

Present Post Graduation: Digital Marketing and Communication

• Mudra Institute of Communications Ahmedabad

Jun. 2017 – Jun. 2018 Bangalore, Karnataka

Bachelor of Technology: Mechanical Engineering

Christ University - Bangalore

SKILLS

Business Development	Expert	B2B Sales	Expert
Lead Generation	Experienced	Communication and Networking	Experienced
Advertising Strategies and Event Management	Skilful	Market Research and Strategic Planning	Skilful
Negotiation	Experienced	Digital Marketing	Skilful